http://www.bcteenchallenge.com/privacy-policy

Need Help?
Privacy Policy
Privacy PolicyOur Commitment to PrivacyProtecting the privacy and confidentiality of personal information is an important aspect of the way Adult and Teen Challenge conducts its business. Collecting, using, and disclosing personal information in an appropriate, responsible, and ethical manner is fundamental to Adult and Teen Challenge’s daily operations. Adult and Teen Challenge Society of BC strives to protect and respect personal information of its donors, employees, students, and so on in accordance with all applicable regional and federal laws. Each staff member of Adult and Teen Challenge must abide by this organization’s procedures and practices when handling personal information.ApplicabilityThis Privacy Policy informs everyone of Adult and Teen Challenge’s commitment to privacy and establishes the methods by which privacy is ensured. This Privacy Policy applies to all personal information within Adult and Teen Challenge’s possession and control.Personal information is defined as any identifying information about an individual or group of individuals, including name, date of birth, address, phone number, e-mail address, social insurance/security number, nationality, gender, health history, financial data, credit card numbers, bank account numbers, assets, debts, liabilities, payment records, credit records, loan records, opinions, and personal views.Business information is defined as business name, business address, business telephone number, name(s) of owner(s), executive officer(s), and director(s), job titles, business registration numbers, and financial status. Business information is treated and handled with the same level of confidentiality, privacy, and respect as personal information.Consent occurs and is obtained when an individual signs an application or other form containing personal information, thereby authorizing Adult and Teen Challenge to collect, use, and disclose the individual’s personal information for the purposes stated on the form or in the Appropriate Use section of this policy.Implied consent is granted by the individual when he/she signs the application or form. This allows Adult and Teen Challenge to obtain or verify information from third parties (such as banks, credit bureaus, lenders, or insurance companies) in the process of assessing the eligibility of an individual, customer, client, job applicant, or business partner.Appropriate UseAdult and Teen Challenge collects and uses personal information solely for the purpose of conducting business and developing an understanding of its donors. Adult and Teen Challenge hereby asserts that personal information will only be used for the following purposes:Mailing lists for newsletters.Need for contacting donors.Tax purposes.Policy StatementsAdult and Teen Challenge Society of BC assumes full accountability for the personal information within its possession and control.Adult and Teen Challenge obtains personal information directly from the individual to which the information belongs. Individuals are entitled to know how Adult and Teen Challenge uses personal information and this organization will limit the use of any personal information collected only to what is needed for those stated purposes. Adult and Teen Challenge will obtain individual consent if personal information is to be used for any other purpose. Adult and Teen Challenge will not use that information without the consent of the individual.Under no circumstances will Adult and Teen Challenge sell, distribute, or otherwise disclose personal information or contact lists to third parties. However, limited disclosure may be required as part of Adult and Teen Challenge fulfilling its stated business duties and day-to-day operations. This may include consultants, suppliers, or business partners of Adult and Teen Challenge, but only with the understanding that these parties obey and abide by this Privacy Policy, to the extent necessary of fulfilling their own business duties and day-to-day operations.Adult and Teen Challenge will retain personal information only for the duration it is needed for conducting business. Once personal information is no longer required, it will be destroyed in a safe and secure manner. However, certain laws may require that certain personal information be kept for a specified amount of time. Where this is the case, the law will supersede this policy.Adult and Teen Challenge vows to protect personal information with the appropriate security measures, physical safeguards, and electronic precautions. Adult and Teen Challenge maintains personal information through a combination of paper and electronic files. Where required by law or disaster recovery/business continuity policies, older records may be stored in a secure, offsite location.Access to personal information will be authorized only for the employees and other agents of Adult and Teen Challenge who require the information to perform their job duties, and to those otherwise authorized by law.Adult and Teen Challenge’s computer and network systems are secured by complex passwords. Only authorized individuals may access secure systems and databases.  Active files are kept in locked filing cabinets.Routers and servers connected to the Internet are protected by a firewall, and are further protected by virus attacks or “snooping” by sufficient software solutions.  Personal information is not transferred to volunteers, summer students, interns, or other non-paid staff by e-mail or any other electronic format.Adult and Teen Challenge’s Web site also discloses its personal information practices and agrees to have its privacy practices reviewed by a lawyer. Individuals inputting data into the Web site will be notified of:Personally identifiable information about the individual that is collected from the Web site or through affiliate site.Information about the organization collecting the data.How the data will be used.With whom the data may or may not be disclosed.What options are available to the individual regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information.The information technology security procedures in place that protect against the destruction, loss, theft, alteration, or misuse of personal information under Adult and Teen Challenge’ possession and control.How the individual may access and correct any inaccuracies in their personal information. Adult and Teen Challenge may share compiled demographic information with its business partners and/or advertisers, but no personal information that can identify any individual person shall be disclosed.This Web site may contain links to other sites, but Adult and Teen Challenge is not responsible for the privacy practices of other organizations’ sites.While IP addresses will be logged in order to administer the site, track visitor movement, and gather demographic information, these IP addresses will not be linked to any personally identifiable information.Site visitors are given the choice to opt out of having their personal information used at the point where the information is gathered.  In most instances, Adult and Teen Challenge will grant individuals access to their personal information upon presentation of a written request and satisfactory identification. If an individual finds errors of fact with his/her personal information, please notify Adult and Teen Challenge as soon as possible to make the appropriate corrections. Should Adult and Teen Challenge deny an individual’s request for access to his/her personal information, Adult and Teen Challenge Society of BC will advise in writing of the reason for such a refusal. The individual may then challenge the decision.Adult and Teen Challenge may use personal information without the individual’s consent under particular circumstances. These situations include, but are not limited to:Adult and Teen Challenge is under obligation by law to disclose personal information in order to adhere to the requirements of an investigation of the contravention of a regional or federal, under the purview of the appropriate authorities. An emergency exists that threatens an individual’s life, health, or personal security.The personal information is for in-house statistical study or research.The personal information is already publicly available.Disclosure is required to investigate a breach of contract.ConclusionAny questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy can be addressed by contacting us at 604-575-3930. Adult and Teen Challenge Society of BC will investigate and respond to concerns about any aspect of the handling of personal information. This organization will address concerns to the best of its abilities. If you no longer wish to receive any mail from Adult & Teen Challenge, please contact us at tcaccounting@teenchallengebc.comor 604-575.3930 ext 201.
Why Choose Adult & Teen ChallengeTransformation – Not Treatment Treatment is important, but transformation is key.Adult & Teen Challenge main focus is on Christ. Our programs depend on the power of God’s word to provide our students with a guiding light.
Learn more
Discipleship & EvangelismThrough our Bible-based curriculum, students learn how to apply God’s Word to their lives. They also learn to recognize the Holy Spirit’s work in their lives, invite God to help them overcome their life-controlling problems, and become more like Christ.
Learn more
Long-Term Residential ProgramsOur residential program is a minimum of 12 months in length with an 18 month additional Successful Living component after graduation. This timeframe provides ample opportunity for men and women to confront their destructive choices, their self-sabotaging behaviour, and their unhealthy views. It then gives them a safe place to establish a new “normal”— assured of the love of God and under the guidance of Biblical principles.
Learn more
I want to find the centre that is right for me!
Chilliwack Men's Centre
Abbotsford Women's Centre
Okanagan Men's Centre
I want to make a donation!I want to apply to the program or need more information!
Apply Now
Donate now
Join our mailing list
Name
*
First Name
Last Name
Email
*
Thank you!
We want to pray for you!
First Name Only
*
Prayer Request
*
By entering your prayer request, you are giving Adult & Teen Challenge permission to share the prayer request with both students in the program as well as the staff and Board of Directors.
Email
Only enter your email if you would like a prayer response.
Thank you!
